# Zainab Adnan AlYousif



#### **Contact**

Eastern Province
Al Jawhara AlShattie,
Dammam, KSA,
+966546857866
Zaalyousif1@gmail.com

### Professional Classification and Registration Record 10KN0352546

## **Key Skills**

Collaboration
Problem-solving
Attention to detail
Leadership
Organization

# Activities and Interests

Animal rights activist Sport Reading Drawing and Painting

## **Objective**

I am a talented leader, ambitious and hardworking individual with broad skills and experience in Data analysis, leading project improvements, Quality Patient Safety and Risk Management, and transformational goals. Furthermore, I am adept at handling multiple tasks competently daily and working well under pressure. I instill confidence in others and approach new challenges with an open mind.

### **Experience**

EASTERN HEALTH CLUSTER (EHC), DAMMAM
Director of Central National Health Insurance Contract Management
(2022-Present)

Interpret national guidance and policies on MOH standards with reference to international best practice.

Develop and produce Service line reports for Cluster wide services. Ensure Clinical and Operational systems are maintained, to include maintenance of allocation budget, upload and processing of data, liaising with the Cluster's and Facilities Decision Support departments to obtain activity information and running the patient's process.

Lead on Central National Health Insurance (CNHI) contract management to ensure going with the Transformational requirements.

# EASTERN HEALTH CLUSTER (EHC), DAMMAM Director of Health Corporatization Project (2021–2022)

Leading EHC Corporatization project to reach the organization's legal and sustainable independent entity.

Facilitating the management control over all inputs, processes, and outcomes.

Managing the Healthcare delivery targets specifications of the Central National Health Insurance (CNHI) contract.

# EASTERN HEALTH CLUSTER (EHC), DAMMAM Project Manager (2018-2020)

In-depth insight into the strategic implementation of the rewarding cluster transformation.

Monitoring & Analyzing MOH KPIs and improvement projects.

EASTERN HEALTH CLUSTER (EHC), DAMMAM
Project Manager-COVID-19 Volunteers' Supervisor (2020-2020)

Organized volunteer services: this includes their training, orientation, and support.

# EASTERN HEALTH CLUSTER (EHC), DAMMAM Ada'a Health Supervisor (2018-2019)

Improving health services, and access to the right quality of care at the right time

Improving data quality through monitoring against seven core Data Quality Standards

Improved ownership, leadership, behavioral change, standard methods, and reinforcement to ensure patients are treated reliably and consistently

#### MINISTRY OF HEALTH (MOH)-ADA'A HEALTH PROGRAM, DAMMAM National Functional Lead Performance Improvement Consultant (2017-2019)

Incorporated the collaboration across MOH, Directorates, and hospitals to improve the quality of health services

A lead of the Northern Region (Jouf & Tabuk) project management. Ensure a considerable growth across facilities and domains

#### MATERNITY & CHILDREN HOSPITAL, DAMMAM Director of Risk Management & Patient Safety (2016-2019)

Designing and implementing an overall risk management process for the organization.

Developed OVR report.

Leading ESR, CBAHI, ESR, JCI Accreditation 2018-2019.

Enforced compliance on patient safety indicators by performing direct observation via patient safety tracers on on-going basis and audit activities.

# MATERNITY & CHILDREN HOSPITAL, DAMMAM Ada'a Health Performance Improvement Officer (2015-2019)

Providing support to the concerned health facilities regarding daily activities to ensure the project's continued progress.

Ensure that the organization's performance change team is trained to collect data and identify and implement improvement initiatives.

Coordinating with the health facility to collect, review and verify data, and identify points of inconsistency between the data.

# MATERNITY & CHILDREN HOSPITAL, DAMMAM Risk Manager Officer (2013-2015)

Communicate risk policies and processes for an organization.

Provide hands-on development of risk models and operational risk, assure controls are operating effectively, and provide research and analytical support.

EASTERN HEALTH CLUSTER (EHC), DAMMAM Nursing Supervisor (2010-2012)

### Languages

Arabic (Native) English (Advanced)-(IELTS 6.5 Taken in 2020)

### **Computer Skills**

MS Office (Word, Excel, Outlook, PowerPoint, OneNote, Access) Google Drive (Docs, Sheets, Slides, Forms) Spreadsheets (Excel, Google Sheets) Presentations/Slideshows (PowerPoint, Google Slides) Database Management (MS, SPSS, Minitab) Ensured of implementing customer-service standards; resolved problems Identifying system improvements to meet standards.

Maintained a safe working environment by designing and implementing procedures, rules, and regulations.

#### Nursing Department, DAMMAM Nurse & Head Nurse (2007-2010)

Obtained the Nursing Shift in Charge position in -2007-2008

Obtained the Antenatal Department HEAD/Deputy & Head nurse- 2009-2010

#### **Education**

Imam Abdulrahman bin Faisal University, Saudi Arabia, Dammam, Mcs, Science in Healthcare Quality & Patient Safety

2021- Expected to graduate in 2023

GPA= 4.8/5

Saudi Electronic University, Saudi Arabia, Dammam Bcs, Health Informatics

2016 - 2020 GPA= 3.2/4 2005-2007

<u>Health Science College, Saudi Arabia, Dammam</u> Health Science in the Field of General Nursing

Intermediate University degree in Nursing 2005-2007

## **Major Courses & Training**

Improvement Capability, Patient Safety, Leadership, Person- and Family-Centered Care, and Triple Aim for Populations – Institute for health Improvement (IHI)-2022

Core Application in quality and patient safety- 2022

Principle of Public Health and health promotion-2022

CPHQ – Exam Dec 13,2022

Introduction to the Triple Aim for Populations-IHI-2022

Leading Quality Improvement-IHI-2022

Introduction to Patient-Centered Care-IHI-2022

Interpreting Data: Run Charts, Control Charts, and Other Measurement Tools-IHI-2022

Testing and Measuring Changes with PDSA Cycles-2022

Testing and Measuring Changes with PDSA Cycles-IHI-2022

Teamwork and Communication-IHI-2022

Human Factors and Safety-IHI-2022

From Error to Harm-IHI-2022

Introduction to Patient Safety-IHI-2022

Responding to Adverse Events-IHI-2022

Executive Management Professional Diploma-2020

KPIs certificate -MOH 2019

Strategic certified Expert Balance performance cards-BSC -Sep 2019 (European Academy of Executive Leaders)

International License Program for Entrepreneurship- Sep 2019 (European Academy of Executive Leaders)

Specialist Project Management- Sep 2019 (European Academy of Executive Leaders)

General Electric GE Change

Agent training 2015- 2017

Mckinsey training for MOH Ada'a Health Functional Lead 2017-2018

Notting Hill College Manchester, United Kingdom, Manchester, Diploma. Health Management Executive (2014)

American University of Delaware, USA, Delaware- Professional Diploma, Health Management Professional Master of Business Administration (2014)

Certified Hospital Surveyor- 2014

Certified of Healthcare quality-2014

Risk Management & Patient Safety training -2013

Advanced Leadership in Healthcare Training -2013

Oxford Leading Training Organization - 2011

#### **Awards**

EHC- Letter of appreciation-2022

EHC- Letter of appreciation-2021

EHC- Letter of appreciation for KPIs, management and data analysis 2019-2020

EHC-WAZEN Program award-2020

CBAHI Accreditation and participation-2019

Ada'a certification for Hajj participation-2018

KSA National second place best Improvement Project -2017

His excellence Best National TOP 5 Change Agents over the kingdom-2016 Patient Centered Program leader for MCH -2016

JCI Accreditation lead participation- 2014 Best Nursing Supervisor -2011

Best Shift in charge of Ob Gyne -2010

Best Nurse of Ob Gyne -2009